人人影視傾情奉獻
翻譯  草草
翻譯  小飯
翻譯  肉松
翻譯  杏仁斯嘉麗
翻譯  ET外星人
時間軸  行遠
顧問  老杜
后期  餓得慌
校對  草草
總監  草草
紙牌屋
第四季  第四集
不到20%的人愿意看到
Less than 20% are comfortable
總統和副總統有任何親屬關系
with a president and a vice president being related in any way.
不到10%的人支持從未當選過公職的人
Less than 10% approve of someone who's never held elected office.
但如果我們能扭轉局面呢
But if we can move the needle...
提升40個百分點嗎
Forty points?
要看我們怎么說
It's how we frame it.
她的支持率不錯  比我還高
Her favorables are decent. They're better than mine.
是對人不對事  就她作為聯合國大使而言
In a void, but when it comes to her time as the UN ambassador,
支持率就猛跌了
they fall off a cliff.
表現和經驗是重要因素
Performance and experience are big factors.
那我們得強調她的優點而非軟肋
Then we have to amplify her strengths, not her weaknesses.
我們需要一個有價值的副總統
We're looking for a VP who's an asset.
這項調查表明她不是
This research proves she isn't.
你的工作不是勸我放棄  而是想辦法說服大家
Your job is not to dissuade me, but to figure out how we sell it.
先生  可選的人很多
Sir, there are so many people to choose from.
如果目標是獲選
If the goal is to win,
-我們在不遺余力...  -賽斯
- and we're bending over backwards-- -Seth.
總統要我們制定計劃
The president asked us to develop a plan,
那我們就制定計劃
so that's what we'll do.
去我辦公室等我
I'll meet you in my office.
-您知道他是對的  -當然了
- You know he's right. - Well, of course he's right.
或許我們可以給她點別的
Maybe we offer something else.
她不會聽的
She won't listen.
莉安呢
What about LeAnn?
我也在考慮那個
Yes, I was thinking that, too.
問題是怎么讓她配合
Question is how to co-opt her.
她喜歡支票
She likes paychecks.
不  光錢不行  她想要政治影響力
No, it's gotta be more than money. She wants coattails.
我跟克萊爾交換
We swap Claire's for mine.
-競選經理嗎  -我們需要新鮮血液
- Campaign manager? - We could use some fresh blood.
這我同意  但莉安
That I agree with, but LeAnn?
沒法保證我們能控制她
I mean, there's no guarantee that we can control her.
但如果她能說服克萊爾改主意
Yeah, but if she can convince Claire to change her mind,
那對我就足夠了
that's all I need.
是
Yes.
戰況室都等您了  先生
They're ready for you in the Situation Room, sir.
我就過去
I'll be right there.
如果有必要你可以跟她合作
You could work with her if you had to.
我不非得喜歡她才能跟她合作
I don't have to like her to work with her.
-很好  打電話吧  -您還想讓賽斯知情嗎
- Good, make the call. - You still want Seth on the plan?
是的  直到莉安同意  我需要擔心他嗎
Yes, until LeAnn's on board. Do I have to worry about him?
我們挖得很深  他的電郵和手機記錄沒問題
We dug pretty deep. Nothing in his emails or phone records.
他聰明  知道掩蓋蹤跡
He's smart enough to cover his tracks.
我去跟他談談
I'll talk to him.
-你覺得這幅畫如何  -我不知道
- What do you think of this painting? - I'm not sure.
沃克和我有一晚曾坐在這里  盯著掛在這兒
Walker and I sat here one night, stared up at a painting,
現在在總統辦公室的那副藍色的畫看
the blue one that's in the Oval now.
這副是后換的
They replaced it with this.
那不是美國國旗
That's not the American flag.
不  是南軍的旗
No, it's the rebel flag...
沉入虛無
sinking into oblivion.
那是閃電嗎
Is that a lightning bolt?
我以為是的...
Oh, I assume...
除非是想把船畫成獨角獸還沒畫好
Unless it's just a bad attempt at making the ship a unicorn.
你看出來了嗎
Do you see that?
色彩不錯
Colors are nice.
我真不喜歡
I hate it.
那我也不喜歡
I guess I hate it, too.
我想在白宮
I suppose it's not a good idea to have
掛聯邦旗大概不是個好主意
the Confederate flag hanging here in the White House
尤其經歷了南卡的事
after everything that's happened in South Carolina.
雖然它是在下沉
Even if it is sinking.
你覺得我們該掛什么
What do you think we should put up?
我不知道  您更喜歡的東西
I don't know. Something you like better.
你帶那支我簽字的馬克筆了嗎
Do you have that marker I sign things with?
把你的手放在墻上
Put your hand up on the wall.
-先生  -放在墻上
- Sir? - Put it on the wall.
手指伸開一點
Spread your fingers a little bit.
等等  好了
Wait. Okay.
嗯  今天就玩到這兒吧
Yeah... That's enough fun for today. -
道格  我不知道該怎么做到他要我做的事
Doug, I don't know how to do what he's asking me to do.
-沒有魔法...  -泄露事件
- There is not some magical-- - The leaks.
-是你嗎  -你認真的嗎
- Was it you? - Are you serious?
非常認真
Very.
我像其他人一樣上交了我的通訊記錄
I handed over all of my correspondence, just like everyone else.
那不能證明什么
Doesn't prove anything.
我是在挽救他的競選
I'm trying to save this campaign.
如果我想搞破壞  讓總統自己來就好
If I wanted to sabotage it, I'd let the president do it himself,
而不是在副總統的事上跟他對著干
instead of fighting back on this VP thing.
或許那只是裝樣子
Or that's just a cover.
去年你不在的時候
I've been in the trenches for the past year
我一直在第一線  現在你還懷疑我
while you've been gone, and now you doubt me?
我不需要這套
I don't need this.
你得到這份工作是靠挖丑事
You got this job by digging up dirt.
如果你到現在還不信任我
If you can't trust me by now,
我不知道我還在這兒干嗎
I don't know what I'm doing here.
你是說你想辭職嗎
Are you saying you wanna resign?
那是我最不想的了
That is the last thing that I want,
但你沒有給我留下的動力
but you're not giving me any incentive to stay.
好吧  去它的
All right. Fuck it.
賽斯  我現在選擇信任你
Seth, I'm choosing to believe you right now,
但如果我有一日感到后悔了
but if I come to regret that decision--
你不會的  因為不是我干的
You won't, because it's not me.
我還是認為密查姆有可能
I still think it could be Meechum.
不是他
It wasn't.
-你確定  -完全確定
- You're sure? - I'm positive.
總統也確定
And so is the president.
我可以走了嗎
May I go?
還是你想談談第一夫人的計劃
Or did you want to discuss the plan for the First Lady?
我要打電話  我稍后去你辦公室
I have some calls to make. I'll come to your office after.
給我接莉安·哈維
Get me LeAnn Harvey.
米爾金將住在他家  安東·考斯基
Milkin will be staying with this man, Anton Khalski.
他原本擁有俄羅斯第二大的銀行
He owned the second-largest bank in Russia
直到2013年被佩特羅夫查抄
until Petrov seized it in 2013.
考斯基逃出國境去了愛沙尼亞
Khalski fled across the border to Estonia.
我們讓米爾金的飛機飛往首都塔林
We'll have Milkin's plane fly to Tallinn,
然后他會乘船去薩拉馬考斯基的夏季別墅
then he'll travel by boat to Khalski's summer house on Saaremaa.
明天  我們將解凍米爾金的美國財產
Tomorrow we'll unfreeze Milkin's American assets
并轉移至考斯基的瑞士賬戶
and transfer them to Khalski's Swiss accounts.
考斯基會聯絡他的俄羅斯軍隊朋友
Khalski will reach out to his Russian military friends
然后開始收買他們
and then start buying them off.
俄聯邦安全局在監控考斯基嗎
Are the FSB monitoring Khalski?
密切監控  他們會知道是我們在支持他
Closely. They'll know we're behind this.
-莫斯科如果質問我們呢  -當然是否認
- When Moscow confronts us? - We'll deny, of course.
如果佩特羅夫反應過激  我們是否有所準備
Are we prepared if Petrov overreacts?
第六艦隊在博斯普魯斯海峽附近有部屬
The Sixth Fleet has a presence near the Bosphorus,
我們在北海也有巡航
we have patrols in the North Sea.
-起草命令吧  -先生  可以說一句嗎
- Draft the order. - Sir, if I may?
-我們討論過了  凱茜  -是的  先生
- Yeah, we've discussed this, Cathy. - Yes, sir.
我覺得我必須
I feel obligated
要提出強烈的反對  這將給我們帶來的外交影響
to raise my very strong objections. The diplomatic cost to us--
如果外交好用
If diplomacy were working,
我們根本就不需要考慮這么做了  是吧
we wouldn't have to consider this course of action, would we?
-我已經提出了擔憂  -謝謝大家
- I've voiced my concerns. - Thank you, everyone.
你不會突然讓
You're not going to surprise me
總統接電話打我個措手不及吧
by putting the president on, are you?
不  只有我們  但他告訴我了
No, it's just us. He filled me in, though,
-關于第一夫人的要求  -怎么樣
- on the First Lady's request. - And?
我們想讓你當競選經理
We wanna make you campaign manager.
看你的郵件
Look at your email.
-是什么  -我們的調研
- What is this? - Our research.
結果是一樣的
It all boils down to the same thing.
你們做了幾個民調  又如何
You ran a few polls, so what?
-還有焦點小組  -毫無意義
- Focus groups, too. - Meaningless.
這么低的數字可不是毫無意義
Not these numbers.
克萊爾不能參選  你很清楚
Claire can't be on the ticket. You know she can't.
這事不是孤立的
This isn't something you can isolate on its own.
如果油價飆升至6美元/加侖  你們就完了
If gas prices hit $6 a gallon, you're fucked.
-你們會失去所有關鍵人群  -我們很清楚
- You lose every key demo. - We're well aware.
但如果總統讓克萊爾做他的競選搭檔
But if the president makes Claire his running mate,
那么話題會轉向策略而非經濟
it makes the conversation tactical instead of economic.
這就給了你們時間處理俄羅斯危機
That buys you time on the Russia crisis.
你們解決了那事  對總統的自信
You solve that, confidence in the president
就能轉變成對總統選擇的自信
translates into confidence in his choice--
我打給你不是想聽你游說
I didn't call you to be convinced.
我打來是想給你份工作
I called to offer you a job.
-是為了拆安德伍德夫人的臺  -不僅是因為她
- Only to get to Mrs. Underwood. -This isn't just about her.
我們需要你  你能扭轉競選局勢
We need you. You'll turn this campaign around.
我好驚訝  道格  我以為你不怎么喜歡我呢
I'm surprised, Doug. I didn't think you were very fond of me.
我喜歡人才  總統也是
I'm fond of talent. So is the president.
我忠于第一夫人
My loyalty is to the First Lady.
我只求你跟她談談
All I'm asking is that you talk to her.
這樣吧  如果你把我的調查給總統看
I'll tell you what. I'll show Claire your research
我就把你的調查給克萊爾看
if you show the president mine.
這我可以同意
I can agree to that.
我根本不該跟你說話的  希瑟
I shouldn't even be talking to you, Heather.
我非常擔憂有濫用職權的現象
I'm seriously concerned that there's been an abuse of power.
司法部長女士  斯坦普先生可以見您了
Madam Attorney General? Mr. Stamper, um, is ready to see you now.
我就去
I'll be right there.
我得掛了
I gotta go.
負責行動的探員
The agent in charge of the operation
事后馬上得到了晉升
got a promotion directly after.
-聽著  -瑪莎  如果總統
- Listen-- - Martha, if the president,
或他的手下  如果有人強迫聯調局
or one of his staff... If anyone strong-armed the bureau
追查盧卡斯·古德溫
into pursuing Lucas Goodwin,
你知道  那就是濫用職權
then you know that's an abuse of power.
我就為總統工作
I work for the president.
我正要跟他的幕僚長面談
I am about to sit down with his Chief of Staff.
-法律就是法律  -這是政治  不是法律
- The law is the law. - This is politics, not the law.
不對  你讓我擔任
Not true. You brought me on
副檢察長是因為我正直
as solicitor general because of my integrity.
而我來找你  是因為你也一樣
I am bringing this to you because of yours.
司法部長女士
Madam Attorney General.
我真的得掛了
I really need to go.
如果古德溫的故事有一絲真實性
If a sliver of Goodwin's story holds up...
你怎么知道的
How did you even find this?
你的對手研究團隊聯絡過證人保護計劃的人嗎
Did your oppo team speak to someone in WITSEC?
如果是那樣  這種違法行為...
Because if that's the case, then that sort of breach is not--
-我跟他本人談過  -什么
- I spoke to him myself, personally. - You what?
他來找我的  他找到了我
He came to me. He tracked me down.
我不要沾這事  希瑟
I'm not touching this, Heather.
道格  真是抱歉
Doug, sorry about that.
-沒事  -我剛剛在跟首席法官通話
- No-- - I was just on with the Chief Justice.
-沒事的  快進來吧  -謝謝
- Don't be silly, come on in. - Thank you.
-這邊請  -謝謝你
- This way. - Thanks so much.
我不知道  她當大使時表現可不怎么樣
I don't know. She didn't do that well as ambassador.
經驗不夠
She wasn't experienced enough.
等等  她做過大使
Hold on, she was an ambassador?
-聯合國大使  -克里斯  你不看新聞嗎
- At the United Nations. - Chris, don't you watch the news?
你們多少人也有同感
How many of you feel the same?
除了缺乏經驗  有其他原因嗎
Any other reasons, besides lack of experience?
她在莫斯科情緒失控時很沖動
Well, she was really impulsive when she had that outburst in Moscow.
她根本就不該去
Well, she never should've been there in the first place.
參議院都否決了她
I mean, the Senate voted her down,
她丈夫還是任命了她
and then her husband just appoints her?
哪能這樣
That's not right.
瞧  我喜歡她這個人  但我同意
Okay, see, I like her as a person, but I agree,
她該繼續做她的第一夫人
she should stick to being First Lady.
他是希望你來勸我放棄
So, he's hoping you'll convince me to let it go.
我能掙得比你給的多得多
Look, I'd make a killing compared to what you've paid me,
但我們談過要有所成就
but you and I talked about making a real mark.
我父親真的很喜歡弗蘭西斯
My father really liked Francis.
但作為我父親  我們結婚前一天  他跟我說
But as my daddy, he said to me, the day before we got married,
"你只有一次人生  克萊爾
"You have one life, Claire.
你確定你要跟這個男人共度此生嗎"
Are you sure this is the man you wanna spend it with?"
你怎么說的
What did you say?
我說我不想在懷疑中度過人生
I said I didn't want to live my life full of doubts.
我覺得弗蘭西斯想讓我懷疑自己
Well, I think Francis wants me to doubt myself.
-怎么回事  -我母親  殺蜥蜴呢
- What was that? - My mother... killing a lizard.
相當長的一段時間以來
-我給您開門  夫人  -我自己能開
- I'll get the door for you, ma'am. - I can open the door myself.
小心腳下  地上有血
Watch your step. There's blood on the floor.
我要你親自把這個交給總統
I want you to take this to the president, in person.
-如果可以  今晚飛過去  -當然
- Try to get on a plane tonight if you can. - Of course.
這是給你的
This one's for you.
-是溫的  -至少是免費的
- It's warm. - At least it's free.
我或許得要你們兌現保險了
I may need to cash in my insurance.
怎么了
What's going on?
如果她拿下提名  我會得到什么位置
Tell me what my position would be if she wins the nomination.
是司法部長嗎
Is it the attorney general?
-什么  -算了
- The what? - Never mind.
做競選搭檔嗎
For running mate?
現在考慮競選搭檔太早了  他還沒贏呢
It's way too early for running mates. He hasn't even won.
-我們說的是一件事嗎  -你先說
- Are we talking about the same thing? - You go first.
事不是那么辦的
It doesn't work that way.
是你想找工作
Well, you're the one looking for a job.
你要么告訴我
You can either involve me,
要么就等著
or you can start reading
報紙頭條報道鄧巴泄露婚姻消息
headlines about Dunbar pushing a marriage story.
那會害死你的
That would blow you up.
道格已經起疑了  我沒什么好怕的
Doug's already suspicious. I've got nothing to lose.
怎么樣
So which is it?
盧卡斯·古德溫
Lucas Goodwin.
他是《先驅報》的編輯  是那個...
He was an editor... at The Herald, the one who--
-我們跟他談過  -他不是在蹲監獄嗎
- We spoke to him. - Isn't he in prison?
出來了
Not anymore.
他將于9:30出發
He's scheduled to depart at 0930 hours.
破曉前不久就能到塔林
That'll put him in Tallinn shortly before dawn.
我們的站長與去薩拉馬的護送隊在待命了
Our station chief is standing by with the escort to Saaremaa.
這是行政命令
This is the executive order.
-長官  -凱茜  我已經決定了
- Sir-- - Cathy, I've made my decision.
-他到達后每小時報告一次  -是  先生
- Hourly updates once he lands. - Yes, sir.
非常感謝
Thank you all very much.
告訴道格我準備好了
Tell Doug I'm ready.
請坐吧  莉安
Please, have a seat, LeAnn.
我很高興你同意加入了
I'm delighted you've agreed to come on board.
據我所知是有條件的
It's my understanding there is a condition attached.
是的
Well, yes.
她明白這個條件吧  你跟她談過了
And she understands that condition? You've spoken with her?
抱歉  先生  我沒說清楚
Oh, my apologies, sir. I wasn't clear.
我是指我們的條件  不是你們的
I meant our condition, not yours.
在初選日
On Super Tuesday.
這么大老遠親自送來啊
It's a long trip to deliver this in person.
這種東西
Well, it's not the sort of thing
可不能落入旁人手中
you'd want to end up in the wrong hands.
你要留在華盛頓嗎
Are you staying here in Washington?
不  我馬上回去
No, I'm going straight back.
有什么話需要我帶給第一夫人嗎
Is there anything you'd like me to tell the First Lady?
告訴她今晚就能回復她
Tell her she'll have her answer by this evening.
謝謝  總統先生
Thank you, Mr. President.
歸程一路順風  哈維小姐
Have a safe trip back, Ms. Harvey.
我自己出去吧
I'll show myself out.
相當長的一段時間以來  我和總統已經漸漸疏遠
For quite some time, the president and I have been growing apart.
讓密查姆進來
Have Meechum step in here.
我們曾企圖挽救我們的婚姻
We've attempted to save our marriage,
但雖經過很多努力  我最終認識到
but after great effort, I've come to the conclusion
我們的婚姻已不可挽救
that it can't be saved.
我今天很遺憾地宣布
It is with great regret that I announce today
我將申請離婚
I'm filing for divorce.
-我們得阻止她  -在她到機場之前嗎
- We have to stop her. - Before she gets to the airport?
不是  克萊爾
No, I mean Claire.
您找我  先生
You asked for me, sir?
進來
Come in.
手機和固話...
Both the cell and the landline--
我們進入了封鎖  夫人  我們屏蔽了...
We're on lockdown, ma'am. We had to scramble all the--
封鎖  你在說什么呢
Lockdown? What are you talking about?
請您待在房內
I'm gonna need you to stay in the house.
-什么  -抱歉  夫人
- What-- - I'm sorry, ma'am.
你不能強迫我留在屋內
You can't force me to stay in here.
現在有針對您很可信的威脅...
There is a current, highly credible threat to your life--
我要跟你的上級說話
I need to speak to your supervising--
我是您在達拉斯的保安主管  夫人
I am the head of your detail here in Dallas, ma'am,
我得到命令要保護您安全留在屋內
and I've been ordered to keep you securely in this house.
安德伍德2016
安德伍德加油
Go Underwood!
-聽啊  -笨蛋伍德  笨蛋伍德
- Listen. - Blunderwood! Blunderwood!
知道他們喊什么嗎  "笨蛋伍德"
Do you know what they're chanting? "Blunderwood."
如果我是他們的英語教授
And if I were their English professor,
我會給他們的小聰明打A
why, I would give them all an "A" for cleverness...
但準確性打D
...but a "D" for accuracy.
但做總統就是如此
But that's part of being president.
會樹敵
You make enemies,
大家此刻就能聽到我的一些敵人在外面吶喊
and you can hear some of mine just outside, right now.
所以我很感激你們每個人
So, I am grateful to each and every one of you
今天前來表示對我的支持
for coming out and showing your support today.
因為你們  我們能拿到提名
It's because of you we will win this nomination,
所以我今天來你們大學
and that's why I came to your college today.
當然了  我知道
Now, of course, I knew
今天會有抗議者來
that there would be protesters here today...
我本可以不來
and I could've chosen not to come,
也可以選擇離開時避開他們
or I could choose to avoid them as I leave,
但我不打算那么做
but I'm not going to do that,
因為外面那些學生  你們的同學
because those students out there, your fellow classmates,
我也是他們的總統
I'm their president, too.
不管他們是不是為我投票  我也得帶領他們
And whether they vote for me or not, I have to lead them as well.
所以  一定得傾聽他們  跟他們說話
So, it's important to hear them, to talk to them,
聽他們的想法
to listen to their ideas,
因為就像你們在大學學習
because, just as you're learning in college,
思想的多樣化讓我們都更加明智
a diversity of ideas makes us all wiser,
對你們的總統來說也是如此
and that holds true even for your president.
真正的領導
True leadership
不是逃避與你意見相左的人
is not running away from those who disagree with you,
而是要接納他們
but embracing them,
今天結束后  我就打算這么做
and that is exactly what I intend to do when I'm done today.
我要出去接納那群人
I'm gonna go out and embrace that entire crowd.
我們不該坐軍用飛機嗎
Shouldn't we be taking a military plane?
那會吸引注意
That would draw attention.
放松
Relax.
一切都安排好了  你不會有事的
Everything's been worked out. You're in good hands.
給  睡會兒吧
Here, get some sleep.
今晚要走很久
It's gonna be a long trip tonight.
笨蛋伍德  笨蛋伍德
Blunderwood! Blunderwood!
-有消息嗎  -都安排好了  先生
- Any news? - Everything's secure, sir.
我們愛你  安德伍德
We love you, Underwood!
感謝大家前來
Thank you all for coming out,
包括那些不完全支持我的人
even those of you who don't entirely support me.
-總統先生你真棒  -謝謝
- Way to go, Mr. President! - Thank you.
我想盡量聽聽你們究竟反對我什么
I wanna try to hear what it is that you disagree with me about.
我知道不是每個人都支持我
I understand not everyone's for me.
-停止戰爭  -滾回加夫尼去吧
- No more wars! - Go back to Gaffney!
你好嗎  謝謝你能來
Hello, how are you? Thank you for coming out.
你好  謝謝你能來
Hello, thank you for coming out.
-你很棒  -我們知道你的真實面目
- You're doing a great job! - We know what you are!
你好
Hello.
好了  我來是想聽聽你們的聲音
All right, I'm here to try to listen to you,
但是一個一個說可能會比較好
but probably one at a time is gonna be a little better.
也許我們應該進行一對一的對話
Okay, maybe we could have a conversation, more one-on-one.
這樣很難聽清
It's difficult to hear you.
我知道你們不喜歡什么  但你們支持什么呢
I understand what you don't believe in, but what are you for?
這樣問也許比較好  你怎么樣
That would be a good question. All right, how about you?
你已經沖我喊了有一會兒了
You've been yelling at me for a little while.
你覺得我該在哪些方面有所改變
What do you think I should be doing differently?
-你應該辭職  -好吧
- You should resign. - Well, now,
我沒在請求你為我投票
I'm not asking for your vote,
但如果你是總統  你會怎么做呢
but what would you do if you were president?
你在毀掉我們的國家
You're ruining our country!
我來這里是想聽你們的心聲
I came out here to try to listen to what you wanna say,
但如果你們只是一直尖叫下去
but if all you're gonna do is scream--
有槍
Gun!
-快走  -快帶他走
- Let's go! - Get him out of here.
-快走  快走  -走走走
- Move! Move! - Go, go, go!
有人企圖刺殺總統
There has been an attempted assassination of the president.
弗蘭克·安德伍德總統遭到了槍擊
President Frank Underwood has been shot.
大約十分鐘前發生于華盛頓特區
It occurred about ten minutes ago during a campaign event
安德伍德總統遭槍擊
哈蒙德大學發生刺殺未遂事件
哈蒙德大學的一場競選活動中
at Hammond University in Washington, D.C.
我們尚不清楚總統的傷情有多重
We do not yet know how severely the president has been wounded.
他正在被送往杰弗遜紀念醫院
He is en route to Jefferson Memorial Hospital.
我們不知道他的情況有多嚴重
We don't know how serious his condition may be.
刺殺未遂事件的視頻還沒送到
Footage of the assassination attempt is still making its way to us,
但相信很快就能夠公布
and we expect to have that shortly.
目擊者聲稱
Witnesses are reporting
當時有連續好幾聲槍響
that there was a quick succession of gunshots,
約有四五發
four or five,
槍手是一個人  身份還未確認
a lone gunman whose identity we are still trying to determine.
已得知槍手已被擊斃
We've been told the gunman was killed,
另有至少一名特勤人員遇難
as well as at least one Secret Service agent,
但我們還未得到明確證實
but we don't have definitive confirmation of that yet.
我們也不清楚槍手和特勤人員的身份
We don't yet know who the gunman may be or who the agent is.
-怎么了  -總統遇刺了
- What's happened? - The president's been shot.
導播現在告訴我
I'm hearing now that the president
總統至少腹部中了一槍  也許不止
received at least one gunshot to the abdomen, possibly more,
他緊捂腹部
that he clutched his stomach,
立即倒地
that he fell instantly to the ground,
現場尖叫連連  人群陷入恐慌
and there were screams, people panicking,
場面十分混亂
that it has been very chaotic at that scene.
目前我們獲得的消息很有限
We have very little information at this time,
僅知道總統遭遇槍擊受傷
other than shots were fired, the president wounded.
但如我所言  他還活著
But as I say, he is alive.
我們也還沒得到
We've gotten no official
白宮的官方聲明
statement from the White House as of yet,
不了解總統的具體情況
either the president's precise condition
或是布萊斯副總統的行蹤
or the whereabouts of Vice President Blythe.
有消息稱他目前在白宮  但我們還不能確認
He is believed to be at the White House. We cannot confirm that,
我們也不清楚他是否會出任代總統
nor do we know if he will take over as acting president,
遵照憲法第25條修正案
assuming the duties of the presidency under the terms
承擔總統的職責
of the 25th Amendment to the Constitution.
但如果總統的傷勢
That would seem likely, however,
如我們認為的那樣嚴重
if the president's wounds are as serious
這將很有可能
as we believe them to be.
這是國家的艱難時刻
This is a difficult moment for the country.
這不是我國總統第一次遇刺
It is not the first time that a president has been shot
我和很多人此前都曾經歷過
in my lifetime or in many of yours.
但即便對那些經歷過這種事的人
But even for those of us who have experienced this before,
此事仍觸目驚心  駭人聽聞
it is no less of a shock, it is no less terrifying.
這是檢驗我國堅韌的時刻
It is the moment when our nation's resilience,
檢驗人民團結的時刻
when our collective strength,
最能檢驗一切的時刻
the moment when all of that is tested the most.
我們難以想象
And we can only imagine
第一夫人此時多么痛苦
how difficult it must be for the First Lady.
-弗蘭西斯他...  -邁克爾說了
- Francis-- - Michael told me.
我得回華盛頓
I have to go back to Washington.
那你還耽擱什么
Well, what are you waiting for?
還指望我安慰你嗎
Do you expect me to console you?
不  我只是...
No, I just...
-再見  母親  -克萊爾
- Goodbye, Mother. - Claire.
我希望他死
I hope he dies.
克萊爾  我無法想象你多么難過
Claire, I can't imagine how difficult this must be.
需要我幫忙嗎
Is there anything I can do?
謝謝你來電慰問  副總統先生
I appreciate the call, Mr. Vice President,
但你眼下肯定還有許多事得處理
but I'm sure you've got a lot to take care of right now.
你需要我的幫助嗎
Is there anything I can do to help you?
等我們弄清目前的狀況
I'll be making a brief appearance once we have a better sense of...
我就會進行簡短發言
where things stand.
需要我在場嗎
Would you like me to be there?
這樣最好  讓國家見到第一夫人
I think it would be good, the country seeing the First Lady.
我覺得讓他們見到你臨危不亂更重要
I think it's more important that they see your steady hand.
如果你在我身邊  我會更有底氣
If you're by my side, it would certainly make it steadier.
當然  我都聽你的
Of course. Anything you ask.
我會為你們祈禱  為你們倆
I'm gonna be praying for you. For both of you.
謝謝  唐
Thank you, Don.
好了
Okay.
這邊請  先生
This way, sir.
總統
2014年10月30日
謝謝  先生
Thank you, sir.
有高度機密事務
The acting president needs
需要向代總統報告
to be briefed on a highly classified matter.
沒有軍事機密權限的人請離開房間
Everyone without military clearance, we'll need the room.
槍手開了兩槍
It was in fact two shots.
襲擊者確認死亡
安德伍德在杰弗遜紀念醫院
刺殺未遂事件
一槍擦傷了身體  就在右臂之下
One that grazed the torso just beneath the right arm
另一槍射入了腹部
and the second which entered the abdomen,
多半傷了肝臟
possibly into his liver.
顯然是這一槍造成了最嚴重的傷害
Obviously, it was that shot that did the greatest damage.
據悉  總統目前情況危急
The president is currently reported to be in critical condition.
為保護總統遇害的
The Secret Service agent
特勤局特工名叫艾德華·密查姆
that was killed protecting the president was Edward Meechum.
他是總統安保隊隊長
He is the head of the president's detail,
我們現在可以確定
and we can confirm that now.
他中槍后  在死前
After being shot and before he died,
殺死了身份仍未知的襲擊者
he killed the assailant whose identity is still unknown.
我們正在等待白宮新聞發言人賽斯·格雷森
We're waiting now on a press conference from the White House
召開新聞發布會
from Press Secretary Seth Grayson,
發布會稍后就將舉行
and we expect to have that beginning in just a few moments.
先給我看過兩遍  再對外確認
We confirm nothing unless you run it past me twice first,
-我不希望...  -格雷森先生...
- I don't want-- - Mr. Grayson...
馬上過去  不要有任何傳言  只要事實
I'm on my way. We don't want any rumors, only facts.
有名學生宣稱是特勤局的人
There's a student who's claiming it was the Secret Service
-開的第一槍  -我剛說了什么
- who fired the first shot. - What did I just say?
-別拿這種屁話浪費我時間  -先生
- Do not waste my time with that bullshit. - Sir,
媒體在等了
the press is waiting.
行  我馬上過去  我的...
All right, I'm... I'm coming. Uh, where's my...
今日午后12:38  副總統唐納德·布萊斯
At 12:38 this afternoon, Vice President Donald Blythe
由內閣任命為代總統
was authorized as acting president by the cabinet.
目前他正與內閣會面
He is currently meeting with them.
約20分鐘前  第一夫人在安德魯空軍基地降落
Approximately 20 minutes ago, the First Lady landed at Andrews.
她不久就會達到醫院
She is expected to arrive at the hospital shortly.
-安德伍德夫人  -他怎么樣
- Mrs. Underwood. - How is he?
他們還在手術室里  大概還得要幾小時
They're still in the OR. Probably a few hours left to go.
他能保住命嗎
Is he going to live?
他被直接擊中肝臟  肝臟部分破裂
He took a direct hit to his liver, which is partially shattered.
幸運的是  左葉有一部分幾乎完好無損
Fortunately, part of the left lobe is mostly intact.
我們認為  他有很大幾率挺過手術
Now, we think there's a decent chance he will survive surgery,
但即便如此  真正的難關在術后才開始
but even if he does, that's when the real fight begins.
我想見他
I'd like to see him.
手術一結束我就告訴您
As soon as he's out, I'll make sure you know.
好  謝謝
Okay, thank you.
我建議取消這次行動
I'd recommend we call off this operation,
現在就讓飛機調頭
we turn the plane around now.
我不同意  我們精心計劃過了
I disagree. It's well planned.
而且總統已經簽字了
The president already signed off.
總統可能挺不過來
The president might die.
-國務卿女士  -不準這樣說  凱茜
- Madam Secretary... - We'll have no talk like that, Cathy.
抱歉  先生
My apologies, sir.
我想說的是
What I am trying to say is that
針鋒相對的風險太大了
it is too risky to antagonize--
我們的目的是嚇唬他們  不是
The point was to scare them, not--
在最高指揮官
To do anything of this nature
無法工作時做這種事
while the commander in chief is incapacitated,
-俄羅斯人會利用這時機  -我們現在高度警戒
- the Russians will take advantage-- - We're at high alert.
我們準備好面對一切可能了
We're prepared for all eventualities.
不能把軍隊當成故障保險
We don't want the military to be the fail-safe here.
副...總統先生
Mr. Vice... Mr. President...
我認為  執行總統簽署的命令
I believe it is our duty to carry out the orders
是我們的職責
that the president signed.
-情況已經變了  -計劃依然可行
- The circumstances have changed. - The plan is sound.
您想怎么辦  先生
So, what would you like to do, sir,
繼續還是終止任務
continue the mission or abort?
我想再考慮考慮
Uh, I... I wanna think on it.
按計劃他將在兩小時后降落
He's scheduled to land in two hours.
我只想
I just want...
我得考慮一下  我們休息一下吧
I've gotta think. Let's take a break.
我得整理整理思緒
I, uh, I need to process all this.
先生
Sir?
總統權衡過一切
The president weighed everything--
凱茜說得很有道理
Cathy brought up some good points.
她從最開始就反對這件事
She's been against this from the very beginning,
但總統明確
but the president clearly--
給我點時間  道格  求你了
Just give me some time, Doug, please?
在我耳邊吼的人太多了
I've got too many people barking in my ear.
總統已經做完手術
The president is out of surgery,
他病情穩定但依然危重
and he is in stable but critical condition.
聽我說  聽我說  我們要有序得來
Excuse me! Excuse me! We are going to keep this orderly.
先讓薩克遜醫生發表完聲明
Dr. Saxon will finish his statement,
然后我們再回答你們的問題  謝謝
and then we'll answer your questions. Thank you.
手術進行了6小時28分鐘
The surgery lasted six hours, 28 minutes.
切除了四分之三的肝臟
Three quarters of his liver was removed.
肝臟  哪怕只剩四分之一
A liver, even one quarter of a liver,
都有能力在六至八周內再生
has the ability to regenerate within six to eight weeks.
我們每小時都會對他進行血檢
We will be conducting blood tests every hour.
監測肝酶水平  血氨水平  凝血酶原時間
Enzymes, ammonia levels, PT times,
這些在聲明材料上都有說明
I believe these are all explained in the handout.
司法部確認了槍手身份
...醫學報告  我們馬上就繼續
...the medical report, live from the White House,
白宮的現場直播
which we will return to shortly.
但我們在密切關注一則重大新聞
But we have breaking news we're following.
此前的報道稱  未遂刺客是
The would-be assassin was previously reported
俄亥俄州代頓的約翰·卡萊爾
as John Carlyle from Dayton, Ohio,
但現在司法部的消息源稱
but sources in the Department of Justice now say
這其實是盧卡斯·古德溫的化名
this was actually an alias for Lucas Goodwin,
他曾是《華盛頓先驅報》的編輯
a former editor at The Washington Herald
兩年前被判犯下了網絡恐怖主義罪
who was convicted of cyberterrorism nearly two years ago.
■
目擊者錄像
如果我們暫停這段手機拍攝的槍擊視頻
Now, if we freeze this cell phone footage of the shooting
然后將槍手的臉與古德溫的照片進行對比
and we compare the shooter's face to this picture of Goodwin...
■
《華盛頓先驅報》提供照片
目擊者錄像
對比結果驚人
well, the comparison is striking
似乎也證實了
and would seem to confirm
來自司法部消息源的說法
what we're hearing from our sources in the DOJ,
即古德溫已于近日獲釋
who say Goodwin was recently released
并加入了證人保護計劃
and is in a witness protection program.
感覺好怪  想到我...
It's so strange to think that I--
多久  也就兩小時前吧  還不到
It was, what? Just two hours before? Less than.
他是什么反應
How did he react?
他很冷漠吧  我看不透他
He was cold, I guess. I couldn't really read him.
他看起來好虛弱
He looks so weak.
要我回華盛頓嗎
Should I come back to Washington?
看看接下來幾天的情況吧
Let's see how the next couple of days go.
隨時通知我  我立馬上飛機
Well, just say the word, I'm on a plane.
好吧  謝謝  莉安  晚安
All right, thank you, LeAnn. Good night.
晚安
Good night.
弗蘭西斯  能聽到嗎
Francis, can you hear me?
弗蘭西斯
Francis.
我剛跟艾迪的父母通了話  夫人
I just spoke to Eddie's parents, ma'am.
您說您想給他們打電話
You said you wanted to call them?
是的  謝謝
Yes, thank you.
艾德華不止是位英雄  密查姆太太
Edward was more than a hero, Mrs. Meechum.
他是我們的朋友
He was our friend.
我非常遺憾您失去了兒子
I'm so sorry for your loss.
如果有什么我能為您
Please, let me know if there's anything
和您的家人做的  務必告訴我
I can do for you and your family.
您隨時可以給我打電話
You can call me anytime.
是的  太太  這是我的私人號碼
Yes, ma'am, that is my private number.
我再次深表遺憾
And again, I'm so sorry.
-盧卡斯·古德溫  -我們不知道他出獄了
- Lucas Goodwin? - We didn't know he was out.
怎么可能  他被釋放了你卻不知道
How can that happen? He's released and you didn't know--
夫人  說到威脅
Ma'am... as far as threats go,
我們最近幾乎都在忙著應付您
we've been far more occupied with you lately.
我希望我們能合作  因為我需要您的幫助
I'm hoping that we can work together, because I need your help.
-怎么幫  -副總統
- How? - The vice president.
我們談過了  我告訴他我會陪他出面
We spoke. I told him I would appear with him.
不是聲明的事
Not the statement.
他現在有個決定難以定奪
He's having trouble making a decision.
您能跟我一起回白宮嗎
Can you come back to the White House with me?
這事很嚴重  夫人
It's serious, ma'am.
我可以在路上跟您說明情況
I can fill you in on the way.
我去拿我的東西
I'll grab my things.
我不能讓你進去  先生
I can't let you go any farther, sir.
我是他的幕僚長
I'm his Chief of Staff.
抱歉  先生
I'm sorry, sir.
現在只有醫生和第一夫人可以進去
Only doctors and the First Lady for now.
克萊爾
Claire.
你好
Hello.
你好嗎
How are you?
-累壞了  -肯定的
- Exhausted. - I'm sure.
你一定也累壞了
You must be, too.
有太多東西我不了解  快把我...搞暈了
There's so much I don't know. It's... overwhelming.
先生  我已向第一夫人說明了米爾金行動
Sir, I briefed the First Lady on the Milkin operation.
考慮到她曾與俄羅斯有過直接交涉
I thought she might have some insight,
我想也許她會有一些見解
given her experience working directly with Russia.
我知道已經有很多人為你出謀劃策了
I know you've had a lot of people weigh in already.
我重視你的建議  克萊爾  我很高興你能來
I value your input, Claire. I'm glad you're here.
-道格拉斯  能讓我們單獨談談嗎  -當然
- Douglas, will you give us a minute? - Of course.
我會跟內閣在一起  先生
I'll be with the cabinet, sir.
你知道人們常說
You know that thing that people say,
上帝不會讓你無法承受
"God never gives you more than you can handle"?
知道
Yes.
我的瑪喬莉  愿主保佑她
My Marjory, God bless her,
她說那是屁話
she said that was pure bullshit.
你丈夫正在與死神搏斗
Oh, listen to me complaining
卻還得聽我抱怨
while your husband is fighting for his life.
沒關系  其實我需要分散下注意
Oh, it's okay. Actually, I need the distraction.
我們談談俄羅斯吧
Let's talk Russia.
我很糾結  我們有架飛機在北海上空盤旋
I'm torn. Uh, we have this plane circling over the North Sea...
-我不知道該怎么做  -你的直覺是什么
- and I don't know what to do. - Well, what does your gut tell you?
我從來就不是靠直覺做事的人
I've never been a gut sort of guy.
如果有把槍指在我頭上...
I mean, if I had a gun to my head...
-對不起  我比喻不當  -沒關系  繼續
- Sorry, that was a poor choice of words. - It's fine. Go on.
我理解總統希望達到的目的
I understand what the president hoped to achieve,
但一想到激怒俄羅斯...
but the thought of provoking Russia...
我這才剛開始了解此事的復雜性
And I'm just beginning to immerse myself in all the complexities.
如果換了弗蘭克  他會怎么做呢
What would Frank do, if he were in my shoes right now?
如果他在這兒  他會告訴你
If he were here, he'd tell you
那是你最不應該考慮的事
that's the last thing you should think about,
因為他不在這兒  你在
because he's not here, you are.
你會怎么做
What would you do?
繼續這項任務還是叫他回來
Proceed with the mission or bring him back?
兩者我都不喜歡
I don't like either.
我只有這兩個選擇
Those are my options.
如果說在弗蘭西斯身邊28年  我學到了什么
Well, if there's one thing I've learned, 28 years with Francis,
那就是他重復多次的那句話
and he said it time and time again,
"如果你不喜歡餐具的擺放..."
"If you don't like the way the table is set..."
-"那就掀桌子"  -沒錯
- "Then turn over the table." - That's right.
他跟我說過不止一次
He's said it to me, more than once.
那你就該這么做  唐納德
Then that's what you should do, Donald.
-但要怎么做呢  -我們一起想想吧
- But how? - Well, let's figure it out.
我們不是早該降落了嗎
Weren't we supposed to have landed already?
我們在待命航線上
We're in a holding pattern.
為什么  出什么事了嗎
Why? Is something wrong?
我只知道我們在待命航線上
All I know is we're in a holding pattern.
道格
Doug.
這架飛機很快就會沒油
This plane's gonna run out of fuel soon.
我們一定要找個地方讓它降落
We're gonna have to put it down somewhere.
我馬上就發表聲明  先跟記者團打聲招呼吧
I'll be making a statement shortly. Let's notify the press corps.
-關于行動嗎  -不  讓美國人民放心
- About the operation? - No, to reassure the American people.
-我在那邊等你嗎  -給我十分鐘
- Shall I meet you in there? - Ten minutes.
內閣呢
The cabinet?
-還在等您的決定  先生  -很好
- Still waiting on your decision, sir. - Good.
走吧
Let's go.
把飛機降落在中國
I want you to land the plane in China.
中國嗎  先生
China, sir?
沒有中國的錢就沒有救市計劃
There's no bailout without Chinese money.
我們把米爾金給他們  他們會有更多籌碼
We give them Milkin, they have more leverage.
先生  那我們就沒有籌碼了
Sir, that gives away our leverage.
我不贊成政權更迭  但那是...
I'm not for regime change, but that just...
這是佩特羅夫最想不到的事
It's the last thing that Petrov is expecting.
他們會索要東西伯利亞的鉆井權
They'll demand drilling access in eastern Siberia.
等他們提出  我們就是兩害中較輕的那個
And when they do, we become the lesser of two evils.
先生  總統從未打算
Sir, at no time did the president
把中國攪進來...
intend on bringing China into the mix...
讓飛機降落在中國領土上
Get the plane on Chinese soil.
并且移交米爾金的資產  這就是我的決定
And turn over Milkin's assets. That's my decision.
-我是向你求助的  -我也給予了幫助
- I asked for your help. - And that's what I gave.
不  中國不在總統的計劃范圍內
No, China wasn't part of the president's plan.
它在代總統的計劃范圍內
It's part of the acting president's plan.
-你準備好了嗎  -好了  就等你了
- You ready? - Yes, whenever you are.
-賽斯  -是  先生
- Seth? - Yes, sir.
女士們先生們  有請代總統
Ladies and gentlemen, the acting president.
請坐
Please, sit.
今天對所有美國民眾來說都是艱難的一天
This is a difficult day for all Americans,
特別是對安德伍德夫人
particularly for Mrs. Underwood,
很感謝她能來到這兒
who is gracious enough to be here,
在我向焦慮的國民講話時  給我力量
to lend me strength while I address an anxious nation.
總統先生
Mr. President!
■
美國歷史上共有四名總統在任上遭暗殺
分別是亞伯拉罕·林肯  詹姆斯·加菲爾德
威廉·麥金利  約翰·肯尼迪
其中林肯和肯尼迪的遇刺最受關注
關于刺殺的動機  細節  甚至兇手身份
都有各種同官方說法不同的"陰謀論"
肯尼迪的遇刺爭議最大
至今仍有大量美國民眾認為
在達拉斯開槍擊中肯尼迪的不止一名槍手
■
此外  美國歷史上還發生過多起刺殺未遂事件
1981年3月30日  里根在離開華盛頓希爾頓酒店時
一個名為約翰·辛克力的男子近距離連發6槍
總統的一名貼身保鏢蒂莫西·麥卡錫  挺身而出擋住了一顆子彈
但仍有一顆子彈打在總統專車上后反彈射入里根體內
擊中了他的肺部
里根隨即被送往喬治華盛頓大學醫院接受手術
手術開始前  神智尚清醒的共和黨人里根
同主刀醫生開玩笑說  "希望你是一名共和黨人"
醫生回答說  "總統先生  今天我們都是共和黨人"
經治療  里根于4月25日重返白宮
■
槍手辛克力刺殺里根  并非出于政治原因
而是想通過這一舉動
引起自己崇拜的好萊塢女星朱迪·福斯特的注意
被捕后  辛克力因"精神失常"而被判無罪
但一直被關在醫療機構接受治療
白宮發言人布雷迪在刺殺中被擊中頭部而造成終身殘疾
此后他同妻子一起致力于推動槍支管制
多年后他幫助通過了美國歷史上最嚴格的槍支管制法案
挺身擋槍的保鏢麥卡錫被射中腹部  經手術后完全康復
從白宮退休后  目前在伊利諾伊州擔任警察局長